Scrimgeour mss., 1968-1981 LMC 2116
Lilly Library
Scrimgeour mss.
1968-1981
Lilly Library
Scrimgeour, Gary J.
LMC 2116
5 Boxes
The Scrimgeour mss., 1968-1981, consists of the correspondence and manuscripts of author Gary James Scrimgeour, 1934-2011, primarily relating to the writing and publication of his first novel, A Woman of Her Times (1982).
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 1981, 1987
Biographical Note
Gary James Scrimgeour was born in Auckland, New Zealand on 15 January 1934. He completed his B.A. at the University of Sydney, Australia, in 1954, his M.A. in English at Washington University in 1959, and his Ph.D. at Princeton University in 1968. He spent his career teaching at various universities, including the University of Florida (1959-1961), Rutgers University (1963-1964), Indiana University (1964-1969), and the National Judicial College (1974-1994). He published his first novel, A Woman of Her Times, in 1982. Scrimgeour died in Reno, Nevada, on 7 June 2011.
Scope and Contents
The Scrimgeour mss., 1968-1981, consists of the correspondence and manuscripts of author Gary James Scrimgeour, 1934-2011, primarily relating to the writing and publication of his first novel, A Woman of Her Times (1982). Correspondents include Scrimgeour, publisher Frank Eugene Taylor, 1916-1999, who acted as Scrimgeour's agent in selling the manuscript to a publisher, as well as editors at Michael Joseph Ltd. in London and G.P. Putnam's Sons in New York, publishers of the novel. Also included is a draft of Scrimgeour's 1968 dissertation for Princeton University, Drama and Theatre in the Early Nineteenth Century. Completing the collection are notes and manuscripts on 19th century drama and dramatists, an unrealized series of publications prepared in the 1970s for Ben Blom, Inc.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Correspondence and II. Manuscripts.
Authors, American--Correspondence; Drama --19th century --History and criticism.; Dramatists, English --19th century.; Indiana University; Theater; Scrimgeour, Gary J.
- I. Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with editors at Michael Joseph, Ltd. in London and Putnam's in New York, 1981, Jan.-June. (Box 1)
- II. Manuscripts (Box 1)
  - A Woman of Her Times
    - 1st draft notes, etc., 1981, Jan.-June. (Box 1)
    - Women and War. Part one, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - 1st draft. Drafts, out-takes, original, 1979 (Box 1)
    - 1st draft. Original typescript, 1980, Oct.-Nov.; (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Text as edited by Phyllis Grann, 1980, Nov. (Box 1)
    - 1st revision by author (photocopy), 1981, Jan.-Feb. (Box 2)
    - 2nd edited text by Grann, 1981, Feb. (Box 2)
    - Second revision by author, 1981, Mar. (Box 2)
    - Final version sent for copy-editing, 1981, Mar.-Apr. (Box 3)
    - Out-takes during copy editing, 1981, May 1 (Box 3)
    - Edited text, 1981, June. (Box 3)
    - undated. (Box 3)
    - Final version of text. Photocopy, (6 folders) (Box 4)
    - Author Galleys (Box 4)
    - Master galleys, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Final-final pages galleys (Box 4)
  - Drama and Theatre in the Early Nineteenth Century (Box 4)
    - Dissertation for Princeton University, 1968; (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - 19th century drama and dramatists (Box 4)
    - General Introduction (Box 4)
    - Bibliography (Box 4)
    - John Baldwin Buckston, 1802-1879 (Box 4)
    - Edward Bulwer Lytton, 1803-1873 (Box 4)
    - James C. Cross, d.1810? (Box 4)
    - William DiamondThomas John Dibdin, 1782?-1837? (Box 4)
    - Charles Dibdin the Younger, 1767-1833; 1771-1841 (Box 4)
    - Edward Fitball, 1792-1873 (Box 4)
    - John Thomas Haines, 1799-1843 (Box 4)
    - Douglas William Jarrold, 1803-1857 (Box 4)
    - James Kenney, 1780-1849 (Box 4)
    - James Sheridan Knowles, 1784-1862 (Box 4)
    - Matthew Gregory Lewis, 1775-1818 (Box 4)
    - William Thomas Moncrieff, 1794-1857 (Box 5)
    - Richard Brinsley Peake, 1792-1847 (Box 5)
    - Isaac Pocock, 1782-1835 (Box 5)
    - John Poole, 1786?-1872 (Box 5)
    - James Robinson Planche, 1796-1880 (Box 5)
    - George SoaneNotes, 1790-1860 (Box 5)
  - Vol. III: Tragedies. Manuscript (Box 5)
    - Draft essays on drama by decadesManuscripts, 1800-1840; (7 folders) (Box 5)
    - Draft essays on drama by decades, 1790-1819; (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous. Includes research notes, book dealer catalogues, etc., (3 folders) (Box 5)